今天我想做两件我想做的事
today I want to do two things I want to
结束对动物园饲养员和
finish the discussion of zookeeper and
那就说破解这个特殊的
then talk about crack the particular
我最感兴趣的事情
things that I'm most interested in
谈论一个糟糕的动物园饲养员是
talking about a bad zookeeper are the
其API的设计允许
design of its API that allows the
动物园饲养员须为通用动物饲养员
zookeeper to be a general-purpose
真正令人满意的服务
service that really bites off
分配的重要任务
significant tasks that distributed
系统需要，那么为什么会这样呢？你知道为什么吗？
systems need so why is this you know why
这是一个好的API设计，然后
is that a good API design and then the
确实更具体的迷你主题
really more specific topic of mini
事务结果表明，这是一个
transactions turns out this is a
值得了解的想法，所以他们有了API
worthwhile idea to know so they got API
我只是个召回动物园的管理员
and I'm just just a recall zookeepers
基于木筏，所以我们可以想到它
based on raft and so we can think of it
因为它是并且确实是容错的
as being and indeed it is fault tolerant
并且做了正确的事情
and does the right thing with respect to
它有这样一种分区
partitions it has this sort of
通过以下方式增强性能：读取
performance enhancement by which reads
可以在任何副本上处理，并且
can be processed at any replica and
因此，读数可能会变得陈旧，所以我们
therefore the reads can be stale so we
只是要记住这一点，因为我们正在
just have to keep this in mind as we're
浅析动物园饲养员的各种用途
analyzing various uses of the zookeeper
另一方面，动物园饲养员的界面
interface on the other hand zookeeper
确实保证了每一份复制品
does guarantee that every replicas
按顺序处理权利流
process the stream of rights in order
使用所有复制副本，一次一个
one at a time with all replicas
以相同的顺序执行权利
executing the rights in the same order
所以复制品在某种程度上是向前推进的
so that the replicas advance sort of in
他们所有人的状态完全不同于
their states of all than exactly the
同样的方式，所有的操作
same way and that all of the operation
生成的
reads and writes produced by a generated
由单个客户端处理或由
by a single client or processed by the
系统还按顺序既按顺序又按顺序
system also in order both in the order
客户签发了这些证书，并且
that the client issued them in and
给定的连续运算
successive operations from a given
客户端始终看到相同的状态或
client always see the same state or
稍后在正确的流中作为
later in the right stream as the
上一次读取操作权限任意
previous read operation right any
客户端操作正常，因此
operation from that client okay so
在我深入了解API的外观之前
before I dive into what the API looks
喜欢和为什么它是有用的，它是值得的
like and why it's useful it's worth just
思考什么样的问题
thinking about what kinds of problems
动物园管理员的目标是解决或可能是
zookeeper is aiming to solve or could be
希望能解决这样的问题
expected to solve so
对我来说
for me
激励的一个完全核心的例子
a totally central example of motivation
你为什么要用Ooh Keeper
of why you would want to use ooh keeper
这是作为
this is it as an implementation of the
测试和设置VMware FT服务
test and set service that vmware ft
这是必需的，以便任一台服务器
required in order for either server to
当另一个人失败的时候接手
take over when the other one failed it
在VMware中是一个有点神秘的东西
was a bit of a mystery in the vmware
纸
paper
这个测试即时服务是什么？
what is this test instant service how is
您可能知道它是容错的吗？
it may you know is it fault tolerant
它本身是否容忍分区，但是
does it itself tolerate partitions but
动物园管理员实际上给了我们工具
zookeeper actually gives us the tools to
编写容错测试并设置
write a fault tolerant test and set
与VMware完全相同的服务类型
service of exactly the kind that vmware
FT需要具有容错和
ft needed that is fault tolerant and
在分区下做正确的事情吗
does do the right thing under partitions
这在某种程度上是一种中心的事情
that's sort of a central kind of thing
动物园管理员在那里做的事也是
that zookeepers doing there's also a
一堆其他的方式证明
bunch of other ways that turns out
人们使用它，Suki是非常成功的
people use it suki was very successful
人们用它来做很多事情
people use it for a lot of stuff one
人们使用的那种东西就是
kind of thing people use is just to
仅发布配置信息
publish just configuration information
供其他服务器使用，如
for other servers to use like for
当前主机的IP地址示例
example the IP address of the current
对于某些工人来说，这是主机
master for some set of workers this is
仅配置配置信息
just config configuration information
动物园管理员的另一个经典用法是
another classic use of zookeepers to
选一位你知道的大师如果我们想
elect a master you know if we want to
当老师傅失败的时候，我们需要一个
have a when the old master fails we need
让每个人都同意谁是新的
to have everyone agree on who the new
师父是，甚至只选一位师父
master is and only elect one master even
如果有分区，您可以选择一个
if there's partitions you can elect a
主控件使用ZooKeeper基元(如果
master using zookeeper primitives if the
少量规定的大师
master for small amounts of stated
不管你选哪位大师
anyway if whatever master you elect
需要保持一些它需要的状态
needs to keep some state it needs to
让它保持最新状态，就像你可能知道
keep it up-to-date like maybe you know
主要身份等信息
informations such as who the primary is
对于给定的数据块，就像您
for a given chunk of data like you'd
需要在GFS中，主服务器可以存储其
want in GFS the master can store its
动物园饲养员的状态，它知道新的饲养员
state in zookeeper it knows new keepers
不会失去它，如果主人
not going to lose it if the master
坠毁了，我们选举了一位新的大师
crashes and we elect a new master to
将其替换为新的母版只能读取
replace it that new master can just read
就在这个古老的主人公的国度里
the old master state right out of
动物园看守人，并依赖于它实际上是
zookeeper and rely on it actually being
那里
there
你可能想象的其他事情，也许你
other things you might imagine maybe you
像系统工作人员一样了解MapReduce
know MapReduce like systems workers
可以通过创建
could register themselves by creating
小文件和动物园管理员一遍又一遍
little files and zookeeper and again
使用像MapReduce这样的系统，您可以
with systems like MapReduce you can
想象一下，师父告诉工人们
imagine the master telling the workers
写东西要做什么？
what to do by writing things in
动物园管理员喜欢写工作清单
zookeeper like writing lists of work in
动物园管理员和工作人员有点像是
zookeeper and then worker sort of take
这些工作项一个接一个地从
those work items one by one out of
动物园管理员并删除它们，因为它们
zookeeper and delete them as they
完成它们，但是人们使用动物园管理员
complete them but people use zookeeper
因为所有这些问题
for all these things question
嗯
yeah
正是如此，所以问题是，哦，怎么做呢？
exactly yeah so the question is oh how
人们使用动物园管理员，一般情况下
people use zookeeper and in generally
是的，你会的，如果你在竞选的话
yeah you you would if you're running
某个大数据中心，您可以运行所有
some big data center and you run all
您的数据中心中的各种东西会让您
kinds of stuff in your data center you
了解Web服务器存储系统
know web servers storage systems
MapReduce，谁知道您可能会触发什么
MapReduce who knows what you might fire
把一个动物园管理员群放到一个动物园管理员群上
up a zookeeper one zookeeper cluster
因为这个通用的用途可以
because this general purpose can be used
很多东西，所以你知道五个或五个
for lots of things so you know five or
七个动物园管理员的复制品，然后当你
seven zookeeper replicas and then as you
部署您要设计的各种服务
deploy various services you would design
用于存储某些
the services to store some of the
您的一名动物园管理员处于危急状态
critical state in your one zookeeper
群集好的API动物园管理员看起来
cluster alright the API zookeeper looks
就像文件系统一样，它在某些级别上有一个
like a filesystem some levels it's got a
目录层次结构您知道有一个
directory hierarchy you know there's a
根目录，然后也许您可以
root directory and then maybe you could
也许每个应用程序都有自己的SUB
maybe each application has its own sub
目录，所以可能是应用程序的
directory so maybe the application one
将其文件保存在此目录中
keeps its files here in this directory
应用程序2将其文件保存在此
app two keeps its files in this
目录，您知道这些目录
directory and you know these directories
下面有文件和目录
have files and directories underneath
他们
them
其中一个原因就是因为你
one reason for this is just because you
看守人就像刚才提到的是一个
keeper is like just mentioned is a
设计可在多个人之间共享
design to be shared between many
可能是无关的活动，我们只是
possibly unrelated activities we just
需要一个命名系统才能
need a naming system to be able to keep
从这些活动中获得的信息
the information from these activities
截然不同，这样他们就不会被弄糊涂了
distinct so they don't get confused and
误读对方数据
read each other's data by mistake
在每个应用程序中，结果是
within each application it turns out
有很多方便的使用方式
that a lot of convenient ways of using
动物园管理员将涉及创建多个
zookeeper will involve creating multiple
文件，让我们看几个示例，如
files let's see a couple examples like
几分钟后就可以了，好的，看起来
this in a few minutes okay so it looks
就像文件系统一样，这是你不知道的
like a filesystem this is you know not
很深，不是，实际上不是
very deep it doesn't it's not actually
你知道你不能把它当做
you know you can't really use it like a
挂载意义上的文件系统
file system in the sense of mounting it
运行LS和CAT以及所有这些
and running LS and cat and all those
事情只是在内部它
things it's just that internally it
使用这些路径名命名对象，如下所示
names objects with these path names so
你知道这里有几个这样的xy&z吗？
you know one this x y&z here few
当你说话时你知道的不同文件
different files you know when you talk
你派一个RPC动物园管理员对我说
to me you send an RPC - zookeeper saying
你知道，请阅读这些数据，你会
you know please read this data you would
命名您想要的数据，可能加起来
name the data you want maybe add up to
劈开X这里只有一种
slash X there's just a sort of
分层命名方案这些
hierarchical naming scheme these these
文件和目录称为Z节点
files and directories are called Z nodes
结果是有三个
and it turns out it's there's three
你必须了解的对你有帮助的类型
types you have to know about that helps
你为自己保留或解决各种问题
you keep or solve various problems for
我们只有普通的Z节点，如果
us there's just regular Z nodes where if
你创造了一个，它是永久的，直到你
you create one it's permanent until you
删除它有一个股骨Z节点
delete it there's a femoral Z nodes
其中，如果客户端创建短暂的Z
where if a client creates an ephemeral Z
节点动物园管理员会将其删除
node zookeeper will delete that
临时Z节点(如果它相信
ephemeral Z node if it believes that the
客户已经死了，它实际上和它有关
client has died it's actually tied to
客户端会话，因此客户端必须排序
client sessions so clients have to sort
每隔一次发送一个小小的心跳
of send a little heartbeat in every once
一会儿进入动物园管理员进入
a while into the zookeeper into
动物园管理员说，哦，我还活着，我还活着
zookeeper say oh I'm still alive I'm
仍然活着，所以动物园管理员不会删除
still alive so zookeeper won't delete
他们的临时文件和最后一份
their ephemeral files and the last
特征文件可能具有的是
characteristic files may have is
这意味着当你问起
sequential and that means when you ask
要创建具有给定名称的文件，请执行以下操作
to create a file with a given name what
您实际上最终创建的是一个文件
you actually end up creating is a file
有那个名字，但有一个号码
with that name but with a number
附加到Main和ZooKeeper
appended to the main and zookeeper
保证在以下情况下不会重复数字
guarantees never to repeat a number if
多个客户端尝试创建
multiple clients try to create
同时创建顺序文件，并且
sequential files at the same time and
还要始终使用蒙特递增
also to always use montt increasing
序列号的编号
numbers for the for the sequence numbers
它们是文件名的笔，我们会看到
that are pens to filenames and we'll see
所有这些都在示例中出现。
all of these things come up in examples
在一个级别上，RPC的操作
at one level the operations the RPC
ZooKeeper公开接口是排序的
interface that zookeeper exposes is sort
您可能会对您的文件有什么期望
of what you might expect for your files
就是创建RPC，在那里您给它一个
was to create RPC where you give it a
真的要命名一个完整的路径名吗？
name really a full path name some
初始数据和以下各项的某种组合
initial data and some combination of
这些标志和有趣的语义
these flags and interesting semantics of
创造是独一无二的，也就是
create is that it's exclusive that is
当我将CREATE发送到ZooKeeper时，询问
when I send a create into zookeeper ask
它可以创建一个文件，这样您就可以保留您的
it to create a file so you keep your
如果该文件为“是”或“否”，则返回“是”或“否
responds with a yes or no if that file
并不存在，我是第一个客户
didn't exist and I'm the first client
谁想创造它？动物园管理员说
who wants to create it zookeeper says
是，并创建文件该文件
yes and creates the file the file
已经存在的动物园管理员说不或者
already exists zookeeper says no or
返回错误，以便客户端知道它是
returns an error so clients know it's
独占创建和客户端知道
exclusive create and clients know
如果他们是唯一的客户
whether they were the one client if
多个客户端正在尝试创建
multiple clients are trying to create
我们将在锁定中看到的相同文件
the same file which we'll see in locking
样本
samples
客户会知道他们是不是
the clients will know whether they were
他实际上成功地创造了
the one who actually managed to create
该文件
the file
还有删除，还有一件事我
there's also delete and one thing I
没有提到曾经容易的音符有一个
didn't mention is ever easy note has a
版本设置为当前版本号，该版本号
version as a current version number that
随着其修改和删除而前进
advances as its modified and delete
以及其他一些更新操作
along with some other update operations
您可以发送一个版本号，上面写着
you can send an a version number saying
只有在以下情况下才执行此操作
only do this operation if the files
当前版本号为版本
current version number is the version
这是明确规定的，结果会是
that was specified and that'll turn out
如果你担心的是
to be helpful if you're worried about in
多个客户端可能
situations where multiple clients might
正试图在以下位置执行相同的操作
be trying to do the same operation at
同时，这样您就可以传递一个版本
the same time so you can pass a version
只说删除就有存在
saying only delete there's an exists
调用哦，名为xenu的路径是否存在
call oh does this path named Xenu exist
另一个有趣的额外论点是
an interesting extra argument is that
您可以要求查看对
you can ask to watch for changes to
无论您指定的路径名是什么，您都可以
whatever path name you specified you can
假设此路径名是否存在，并且
say does this path name exist and
无论是否存在，它现在都存在，如果
whether or not exists it exists now if
如果你传入的是真的，你就把这只表调好
you set this watch if you pass in true
对于这块表旗，动物园管理员保证
for this watch flag zookeeper guarantees
如果有任何更改，请通知客户端
to notify the client if anything changes
有关该路径名的信息，就像它是创建的一样
about that path name like it's created
或删除或修改，并且进一步
or deleted or modified and furthermore
检查文件是否
the the check for whether the file
存在且手表的设置
exists and the setting of the watch
中的观看信息点
point of the watching information in the
在动物园看守人或原子里，所以什么都没有
inside zookeeper or atomic so nothing
可能会发生在
can happen between the point at which
写入流中的点，该点
the point in the write stream which
动物园管理员查看这条路径是否
zookeeper looks to see whether the path
存在，并且写入流中的点
exists and the point in the write stream
动物园管理员把手表放在哪个位置
at which zookeeper inserts the watch
放进它的桌子里，然后就像是非常
into its table and then that's like very
对于正确性来说很重要，我们还
important for for correctness we also
得到D，然后你会得到一条路径，然后再一次
get D then you get a path and again the
手表旗，现在手表刚刚
watch flag and now the watch just
应用于该文件的内容
applies to the contents of that file
有设定的数据
there's set data
再次对新数据进行路径选择，这
again path the new data and this
条件版本，如果您将
conditional version that if you pass an
倒置，那么实际上只有动物园饲养员
inversion then zookeeper only actually
如果当前版本为
does the right if the current version
文件的编号等于
number of the file is equal to the
你传入的数字好的，让我们看看
number you passed in okay so let's see
我们是如何使用这个的，第一个可能几乎是
how we use this the first maybe almost
第一个非常简单的示例是
this first very simple example is
假设我们在动物园管理员那里有一份文件
supposing we have a file in zookeeper
我们想在里面存储一个数字
and we want to store a number in that
文件，我们希望能够递增
file and we want to be able to increment
这个数字，所以我们可能会保留一个
that number so we're keeping maybe a
统计信息计数，只要客户端
statistics count and whenever a client
你知道吗，我知道我收到了一个
you know I know gets a request from a
网络用户或它将要使用的东西
web user or something it's going to
增加ZooKeeper中计数，并
increment that count in zookeeper and
多个客户端可能希望
more than one client may want to
增加关键的计数
increment the count that's the critical
这是一个例子，所以要分类的是一件事
thing so an example so one thing to sort
让开的是我们是不是
of get out of the way is whether we
实际上需要一些专门的接口
actually need some specialized interface
为了支持客户协调
in order to support client coordination
与仅仅是数据相反，这看起来像是
as opposed to just data this looks like
一个文件系统，我们能不能只提供
a file system could we just provide the
普通读写类文件系统
ordinary readwrite kind of file system
那些标有典型储藏室日期的东西
stuff that dated that typical storage
例如，系统提供了一些
systems provide so for example some of
你们已经开始了，你们都将开始
you have started and you'll all start
很快就会有Ladd3，你可以在其中建立一个密钥
soon Ladd 3 in which you build a key
两个操作所在的值存储
value store where the two operations are
唯一操作是PUT KEY VALUE
the only operations are put key value
所以一个问题是我们能帮你
and so one question is can we do you
了解所有我们可能需要的东西
know all these things that we might want
与动物园管理员的关系，我们能不能就这么做？
to do with zookeeper can we just do them
实验3的密钥具有密钥值
with lab 3 with a key with a key value
把get接口放在这里，所以假设是为我准备的
put get interface so supposing for my I
可能想要实现这个计数功能
want to implement this count thing maybe
我只需用一下就可以实现计数
I could implement the count with just
实验三的密钥值接口使您
lab threes key value interface so you
可能会通过说x来递增计数
might increment the count by saying x
等号让你知道不管是什么钥匙
equals get you know whatever key were
使用该密钥，然后将该密钥X加1
using and then put that key an X plus 1
为什么这是个糟糕的回答是的是的哦
why why is this a bad answer yes yes oh
不是原子绝对是
it's not atomic that is absolutely the
问题的根源在这里，你知道
root of the problem here and you know
抽象地说，只有一个
the abstract way of putting it but one
看待它的方式是两个人的观点
way of looking at it is that of two
客户端都希望递增
clients both want to increment the
同时计数，他们两个都是
counter at the same time they're both
会读到他们都会用GET
gonna read they're both gonna use get to
读一读旧的值，你就会知道10
read the old value and get you know ten
这些人会把1加到10，然后得到11
those gonna add one to ten and get 11
我本来要打给11岁的PUT的，所以现在
and I was gonna call put with 11 so now
我们把柜台加了一，但是
we've increased the counter by one but
有两个客户在这么做，所以我们肯定
two clients were doing it so surely we
最终应该把它增加到
should have ended up increasing it by
两个，所以这就是为什么三号实验室不能
two so that's why the lab three cannot
即使在这个简单的示例中也会使用
be used for even this simple example
此外，在动物园饲养员这类人中
furthermore in the sort of zookeeper
访客可以返回陈旧数据的世界
world where guests can return stale data
不是实验3或GET不允许
is not lab 3 or gets are not allowed to
返回过时数据，但在ZooKeeper读取中
return stale data but in zookeeper reads
可能是陈腐的，所以如果你读了一本陈腐的
can be stale and so if you read a stale
当前计数器的版本并添加
version of the current counter and add
一比一
one to it
你现在写错了值，你
you're now writing the wrong value you
我知道如果30值11，但你会得到
know if 30 values 11 but you're get
返回将1加1后的陈旧值10
returns a stale value of 10 you add 1 to
加11是个错误，因为
that and put 11 that's a mistake because
我们真的应该把12个
we really should have been putting 12 so
动物园管理员还有这个额外的问题
zookeeper has this additional problem
我们不得不担心这一点
that we have to worry about that
该GET不返回最新数据
that gets don't return the latest data
好的，那么在动物园管理员你会怎么做呢？
ok so how would you do this in zookeeper
以下是我在动物园饲养员做这件事的方式
here's how I would do this in zookeeper
原来你需要做你需要做的事
it turns out you need to do you need to
将此代码包装在西门子循环中，因为
wrap this code Siemens in a loop because
不能保证第一次就能成功
it's not guaranteed to succeed the first
时间到了，所以我们只想说虽然是真的
time so we're just gonna say while true
我们将调用Get Data来获取
we're gonna call get data to get the
计数器的当前值和
current value of the counter and the
当前版本，所以我们会说X，V
current version so we're gonna say X V
等于我得到了数据，我们需要说
equals I'm get data and we need to say
最后的名字，我不在乎文件是什么
final name I don't care what the file
名字就是我们只是说好听的，现在我们得到了
name is we just say that nice now we get
我们就会得到一个值和一个版本
the well we get a value and a version
号码可能不新鲜，可能已过期
number possibly not fresh possibly stale
但也许是新鲜的，然后我们会用
but maybe fresh and then we're gonna use
条件PUT条件设置
a conditional put a conditional setting
如果设置数据是设置数据操作
and if set data is a set data operation
返回它实际设置的真实含义
return true meaning it actually did set
否则我们将打破的价值
the value we're gonna break otherwise
只要回到循环的顶部就可以了
just go back to the top of the loop
否则，这里发生的事情就是
otherwise so what's going on here is
我们读到了一些价值和一些版本
that we read some value and some version
号码可能还在，可能是刚出的
number maybe still maybe fresh out of
副本是我们发送的集合数据
the replicas the set data we send
实际上动物园管理员的领导
actually did the zookeeper leader
因为所有的权利都属于领导者
because all rights go to the leader and
这意味着仅将值设置为
what this means is only set the value to
如果版本为实数，则X加1
X plus one if the version with the real
版本最新版本仍为V
version the latest version is still is V
所以如果我们读到最新的数据
so if we read fresh data and nothing
否则就会在系统中发生，就像没有
else is going on in the system like no
其他客户端正在尝试增加
other clients are trying to increment
这就是我们要阅读的最新版本
this then we'll read the latest version
最新值我们将在最新值上加一
latest value we'll add one to the latest
值指定最新版本和我们的
value specify the latest version and our
领导将接受设置的数据
set data will be accepted by the leader
我们会得到肯定的答复
and we'll get back a positive reply to
我们的请求在提交后
our request after it's committed and
我们会休息的，因为如果我们有机会的话我们就完蛋了
we'll break because we're done if we got
这里的数据是陈旧的，或者这是最新的数据
stale data here or this was fresh data
但是到了那个时候
but by the time
我们的设定数据传给了领先者一些
our set data got to the leader some
其他客户端设置数据和其他一些
other clients set data and some other
客户端正在尝试增加其集合
client is trying to increment their set
数据比我们的版本早到那里
data got there before us our version
号码将不再是新的
number will no longer be fresh in either
在这些情况下，此设置数据将失败，并且
those cases this set data will fail and
我们会拿回错误响应的
we'll get an error response back it
不会跳出圈子，我们就走
won't break out of the loop and we'll go
回来再试一次，希望我们能
back and try again and hopefully we'll
这次成功是的是的所以
succeed this time yes yes so the
问题是这会不会是一个While循环
question is could this it's a while loop
否则我们保证永远不会结束
or we guaranteed is ever going to finish
不，不，我们不是真的有保证
and no no we're not really guaranteed
我们会在练习中完成你的训练
that we're gonna finish in practice you
例如，如果我们的复制品是
know so for example if our replicas were
朗读被切断了与领导的联系
reading from is cut off from the leader
并永久地提供给我们陈旧的数据
and permanently gives us stale data then
你知道，也许这不会奏效
you know maybe this is not gonna work
出去，但你知道，但在现实生活中
out but you know but in real life well
在现实生活中，你知道的领导者
in real life the you know leaders
把所有的复制品都推向
pushing all the replicas towards having
与领导者相同的数据，这样你就知道
identical data to the leader so you know
如果我们这里只有陈旧的数据
if we just got stale data here probably
当我们回去的时候，你知道也许我们应该
when we go back you know maybe we should
睡10毫秒之类的
sleep for 10 milliseconds or something
在这一点上，但是当我们回到这里的时候
at this point but when we go back here
最终我们会看到最新的
eventually we're gonna see the latest
数据显示，在这种情况下
data the situation under which this
可能真的是相当坏的消息是如果
might genuinely be pretty bad news is if
有非常高的持续负荷
there's a very high continuous load of
来自您知道的客户的增量，如果我们
increments from clients you know if we
有一千个客户都想要
have a thousand clients all trying to do
增加的风险是可能没有
increments the risk is that maybe none
他们中的一些人会成功或者别的什么
of them will succeed or something I
我觉得其中一个会成功，因为我
think one of them will succeed because I
我认为最成功的原因之一是
think one of the most succeed because
你知道第一个拿到
you know the the first one that gets its
将数据设置到引线中将成功
set data into the leader will succeed
而睡觉都会失败，因为他们的
and the rest will all fail because their
版本号都太低了，然后
version numbers are all too low and then
接下来的999人会把数据放进去
the next 999 will put and get data's in
他们中的一个会成功，所以一切都会成功
and one of them will succeed so it all
有一种N平方的复杂性
have a sort of N squared complexity to
接通所有其他客户端
get through all of the all other clients
这是非常具破坏性的，但它会
which is very damaging but it will
最终完成，所以如果你认为
finish eventually and so if you thought
你会有很多客户，你
you were gonna have a lot of clients you
会在这里使用不同的策略
would use a different strategy here this
是好的吗？
is good
或者加载情况是的，如果它们适合的话
or load situations yes if they fit in
记忆，如果不合适也没问题
memory it's no problem if they don't fit
记忆，这是一场灾难，所以，是的，当
memory it's a disaster so yeah when
你用的是动物园看守人，你必须
you're using zookeeper you have to keep
记住，这是对的，这是很棒的
in mind that it's yeah it's great for
100兆字节的东西，很可能
100 megabytes of stuff and probably
对于100G的东西来说太可怕了，所以
terrible for 100 gigabytes of stuff so
这就是为什么人们认为它是储存
that's why people think of it as storing
配置信息，而不是
configuration information rather than
他们是你们大网站的老数据
their we old data of your big website
是的，我的意思是有点像是在看这个。
yes I mean it's sort of watch into this
序列
sequence
然而，如果我们愿意的话，如果我们
yet that could be so if we want if we
我想解决这个问题，让它在高压下工作
wanted to fix this to work under high
加载，那么您肯定会想要
load then you would certainly want to
在我不舒服的时候睡觉
sleep at this point where I'm not well
我修复这件事的方式是我的直觉
the way I would fix this my instinct I'm
解决这个问题的方法是插入睡眠
fixing this would be to insert asleep
这里还有另外两倍的金额
here and furthermore double the amount
它有点像是随机睡眠，
of it sort of randomized sleep whose
随机性的范围在每次我们
span of randomness doubles each time we
失败了，这是一种久经考验的真理
fail and that's a sort of tried and true
策略指数回退是一种
strategies exponential back-off is a
它实际上和救生筏的领头人很相似
it's actually similar to raft leader
选举，这是一个合理的策略
election it's a reasonable strategy for
适应未知数量的
adapting to an unknown number of
并发客户端，所以好的，告诉我
concurrent clients so okay tell me
什么是对的，好的，所以我们正在获取数据
what's right okay so we're getting data
然后看着它的真面目
and then watching its true
所以，是的，所以如果其他人修改了
so yes so if somebody else modifies the
调用集合数据之前的数据可能
data before you call set data maybe
你会收到一个手表通知，嗯，
you'll get a watch notification um the
问题是计时不起作用
problem is the timing is not working in
你的好意喜欢时间的长短
your favor like the amount of time
从我收到这里的数据开始
between when I received the data here
当我把信息发送给
and when I send off the message to the
此新集合数据的引线为零
leader with this new set data is zero
这就是这里要经过的时间
that's how much time will pass here
粗略地说，如果有其他客户被派来
roughly and if some other client is sent
大约在这个时候，它是递增的
in increment at about this time it's
实际上有相当长的一段时间
actually quite a long time between when
该客户端发送增量，并且
that client sends in the increment and
当它以自己的方式通过领导者的时候
when it works its way through the leader
并被送到追随者手中
and is sent out to the followers and
实际上处决了追随者和
actually executed the followers and the
追随者在他们的手表里查一下
followers look it up in their watch
表，然后给我发个通知，所以我
table and send me a notification so I
想
think
它不会给您任何读取结果，或者如果
it won't give you any read result or if
如果你要阅读，你可以在某一时刻阅读
you read at a point if you're gonna read
在这一点上，在那里
at a point that's after where the
发生了应引发的修改
modification occurred that should raise
您将收到通知的手表
the watch you'll get the notification of
在你拿到读数之前看表
the watch before you get the read
回应，但不管怎样，我想没什么
response but in any case I think nothing
这样可以救我们因为
like this could save us because what's
将会发生的是所有的上千个客户
gonna happen is all thousand clients are
不管是什么，我都会做同样的事
gonna do the same thing whatever it is
好的，他们都会再做一次
right they're all gonna do again and set
一块手表什么的他们都会
a watch and whatever they're all gonna
同时收到通知
get the notification at the same time
他们都会做出同样的决定
they're all gonna make the same decision
关于他们都不会去
about well they're all not gonna get to
注意了，因为他们中没有一个人做过
watch because none of them has done the
将数据放在正确的位置
put data yet right
所以最糟糕的情况是所有的客户
so the worst case is all the clients are
从同一点开始，他们都做了一个
starting at the same point they all do a
他们都拿到第一版了，他们都拿到了
get they all get version one they all
设置一个观察点，他们得不到
set a watch point they don't get a
通知，因为没有更改
notification because no change has
发生时，它们都会将集合数据RPC发送到
occurred they all send a set data RPC to
他们中的上千人都是首领
the leader all thousand of them the
第一个更改数据，现在更改
first one changes the data and now the
其他999，并在以下情况下收到通知
other 999 and get a notification when
太晚了，因为他们已经
it's too late because they've already
发送了设置数据，所以有可能
sent the set data so it's possible that
手表可以帮到我们，但在某种程度上
watch could help us here but sort of
我有一款简单易懂的手表
straightforward version of watch I have
如果你想要邮件的感觉
a feeling if you wanted the the mail
我们将在几分钟后讨论这个问题
we'll talk about this in a few minutes
但是无名氏听到了第二次上锁的声音
but the anon heard the second locking
这个例子完全解决了这类问题。
example absolutely solves this kind of
这样我们才能适应第二个问题
problem so we could adapt to the second
从论文中锁定示例，尝试
locking example from the paper to try to
使增量一次一个地发生。
cause the increments to happen one at a
如果有大量的客户，时间到了
time if there's a huge number of clients
谁想做这件事其他问题是关于
who want to do it other questions about
这个例子好的，这是一个例子
this example okay this is an example of
一辆很多人称之为迷你的车
a what many people call a mini
交易好的，是交易性的。
transaction all right it's transactional
从某种意义上说，哇，你知道
in a sense that wow there's you know a
这里发生了很多有趣的事情
lot of funny stuff happening here the
效果是，一旦这一切都成功了，我们
effect is that once it all succeeds we
已经实现了一种原子
have achieved an atomic
计数器权限的读-修改-写
read-modify-write of the counter right
这里的困难在于
the difficulty here
它不是原子的读数
is that it's not atomic the reading the
右读修改右
right the read the modifying the right
原子不是我们拥有的东西吗
are not atomic the thing that we have
从这里拉出来的就是这个序列
pulled off here is that this sequence
一旦它完成了就是原子对的我们
once it finishes is atomic right we
实际上，人和一旦我们必须上
actually man and once we have to be on
我们成功地通过了这一关
the pass through this that we succeeded
我们设法读取增量和写入
we managed to read increment and write
在没有任何其他干预的情况下，我们
without anything else intervening we
我成功地自动完成了这两个步骤
managed to do these two steps atomically
你知道这不是因为这
and you know this is not because this
不是一个完整的数据库事务，就像
isn't a full database transaction like
真实数据库允许完全通用
real databases allow fully general
您可以说开始的事务
transactions where you can say start
事务，然后读取或写入
transaction and then read or write
你喜欢的任何东西，可能有几千种
anything you like maybe thousands of
不同的数据项，不管谁知道
different data items whatever who knows
什么，然后说结束交易和
what and then say end transaction and
数据库将巧妙地提交
the database will cleverly commit the
整个事情就像一个原子事务，所以
whole thing as an atomic transaction so
真实的交易可能非常
real transactions can be very
复杂的动物园管理员支持这一点
complicated zookeeper supports this
你知道的极其简化的版本
extremely simplified version of you know
当你是那种人的时候，我们就能做到
when you're sort of one we can do it
在一块上进行原子操作
atomic sort of operations on one piece
的数据，但这足以获得增量
of data but it's enough to get increment
还有其他一些东西，所以这些是用来
and some other things so these are for
那是因为他们不是一般的
that reason since they're not general
但是它们确实提供了原子性，这些是
but they do provide atomicity these are
通常称为迷你事务，它
often called mini transactions and it
事实证明，这种模式可以制作成
turns out this pattern can be made to
也可以处理其他各种事情，比如
work with various other things too like
如果我们想做测试并设置
if we wanted to do the test and set that
VMware ft要求它可以实施
vmware ft requires it can be implemented
在很大程度上，你知道，也许
with very much this setup you know maybe
如果旧值为零，则我们尝试
the old value if it's zero then we try
将其设置为1，但提供此版本
to set it to one but give this version
你知道，没有其他人插手干预
number you know nobody else intervened
而我们才是真正设法
and we were the one who actually managed
将其设置为1，因为版本
to set it to one because the version
号码没有变，但我是领队
number hadn't changed but i'm leader got
我们的请求，我们赢得了另一个人
our request and we win somebody else
在我们读完之后更改为1，然后
changes to one after we read it then the
领导会告诉我们我们输了所以你
leader will tell us that we lost so you
可以用此图案进行测试和设置
can do test and set with this pattern
另外，您应该记住，这是
also and you should remember this is the
战略
strategy
好的，好的，下一个例子，我想谈谈
okay alright next example I want to talk
是关于这些锁的，我说的是
about is these locks and I'm talking
因为报纸上不是这么说的
about this because it's in the paper not
因为我坚信这件事
because I strongly believe that this
一种锁是有用的，但他们有
kind of lock is useful but they have
他们举了一个例子，在这个例子中，一个合唱团
they have an example in which a choir
有几个步骤，其中一个是我们试图创建的
has a couple steps one we try to create
我们有一个锁定文件，我们尝试创建
we have a lock file and we try to create
锁定文件现在又是一些带有
the lock file now again some file with a
股骨设置为TRUE，因此如果
femoral set to true and so if that
不管成功与否，我们已经获得了
succeeds then or not we've acquired the
锁定第二个步骤，该步骤不会
lock the second step that doesn't
成功，那么我们要等待任何人
succeed then we want to wait for whoever
有没有拿到锁如果这不是
did acquire the lock what if this isn't
TRUE，这意味着锁文件已经
true that means the lock file already
是否存在，我是说，其他人已经获得了
exists I mean somebody else has acquired
锁上了，所以我们要等他们
the lock and so we want to wait for them
把锁打开，他们就会
to release the lock and they're gonna
通过删除此文件来释放锁定
release the lock by deleting this file
所以我们要看“是”
so we're gonna watch yes
好的，我们要看我们要
alright so we're gonna watch we're gonna
呼唤存在，守望是真的
gonna call exists and watching is true
现在事实证明，嗯，好的，而且
now it turns out that um okay and and
如果该文件仍然存在，那么
and if the file still exists right which
我们希望如此，因为毕竟他们
we expect it to because after all they
不存在的话大概会有
didn't exist presumably would have
返回到这里，所以如果它存在，我们希望
returned here so if it exists we want to
等待我们正在等待的通知
wait for the notification we're waiting
对于此手表通知，请调用此
for this watch notification call this
三步一步去什么所以
three and a step for go to what so the
通常的做法是你知道我们叫Create
usual deal is you know we call create
你知道，如果失败了，也许我们会赢
you know maybe we win if it fails we
等待拥有锁的人释放
wait for whoever owns a lock to release
如果我们在什么时候收到手表通知
it we get the watch notification when
此时将删除该文件
the file is deleted at that point this
等完了，我们就回孟加拉
wait finishes and we go back to Mon and
希望我们能试着重新创建文件
try to recreate the file hopefully we
这次会拿到文件的，好的，所以我们
will get the file this time okay so we
应该问问我们自己关于
should ask ourselves questions about
其他客户端的可能交叉
possible interleavings of other clients
我们有四个步骤的活动，所以我们
activities with our four steps so one we
我们肯定知道如果我们已经知道
know for sure we know of already if
另一个客户端在相同的位置调用CREATE
another client calls create at the same
时间到了，动物园管理员领队就要走了
time then the zookeeper leader is going
处理这两个以创建RPC一个
to process those two to create rpcs one
在某一时刻以某种顺序
at a time in some order
所以要么迈克·里德被处决
so either mike reid will be executed
第一
first
否则创建的其他客户端将
or the other clients create will be
被处死的第一个思想首先被处死的是我
executed first minds executed first i'm
会得到一个真正的回报
going to get a true back in return and
获取锁，另一个客户端
acquire the lock and the other client is
保证会得到一份虚假的报税单，如果
guaranteed to get a false return and if
首先要处理的是PC，它们将
there are pcs processed first they'll
得到真正的回报，我保证
get the true return and i'm guaranteed
以获得虚假的报税表，并且在任何一种情况下
to get the false return and in either
在将创建文件的情况下
case the file will be created
所以如果我们同时有
so we're okay if we have simultaneous
对另一个人的处决是一个问题
executions of one another question is
好吧，你知道如果我创造不了
well you know if I if create doesn't
如果我成功了，我会打电话给EXISTS
succeed for me and I'm gonna call exists
如果锁被释放，会发生什么情况
what happens if the lock is released
实际上在Create和
actually between the create and the
存在
exists
所以这就是为什么我说唱我有一个
so this is the reason why I rap I have a
在我周围的刀是存在的
knife around me around the exists is
因为它实际上可能会被释放
because it actually might be released
在我调用Exist之前，因为它可能
before I call exists because it could
早在很久以前就被收购了
have been acquired quite a long time ago
由某个其他客户端执行，然后如果
by some other client and then if the
那么在这一点上文件不存在
file doesn't exist at this point then
这会失败的，我会直接去
this will fail and I'll just go directly
回到这里，转到1，然后再试一次
back to this go to one and try again
同样，实际上也更有趣
similarly and actually more interesting
如果拿着它的人
is what happens if the whoever holds it
现在释放它，就像我调用eXist或
now releases it just as I call exist or
因为我正在与之交谈的复制品在
as the replica I'm talking to is in the
处理我的EXISTS请求的过程中
middle of processing my exists requests
这个问题的答案是
and the answer to that is that the
不管我看的是什么复制品，你知道的
whatever replica I'm looking at you know
它记录或保证权限发生
it's log or guaranteed that rights occur
按某种顺序排列，对吗？
in some order right
所以我正在与之交谈的回复是，这是
so the repla I'm talking to it's it's
以某种方式记录它的进程，然后我的
log its proceeding in some way and my
保证执行Existes调用
exists call is guaranteed to be executed
在右侧的两个日志条目之间
between two log entries in the right
向右流，这是一条，这是一条
stream right this is a this is a
只读请求，并且您知道
read-only request and you know the
问题是有人删除了
problem is that somebody's delete
请求正在处理中，大约在此
request is being processed at about this
时间，所以日志中的某个地方已经过去了
time so somewhere in the log is going
其中一个将是删除请求
either is going to be the delete request
从另一个客户和代表那里
from the other client and the rep and
你知道这是我的思想复制品
you know this is my mind the replica
我在和动物园管理员的复制品谈话
that I'm talking to zookeeper replicas
我在跟他的日志说话我的手表我的
I'm talking to his log my watch my
现有的RPC被处理
exists RPC is either processed
完全在这里处理，在这种情况下
completely processed here in which case
复制品看到的还是文件
the replica sees oh the file still
存在，并且复制副本插入监视
exists and the replica inserts the watch
在此将信息放入其观察表中
information into its watch table at this
指针，然后才执行删除
point and only then executes the delete
所以当删除出现的时候是
so when the delete comes in were
保证我的手表请求在
guaranteed that my watch request is in
副本监视表，它将
the replicas watch table and it will
向我发送通知权利或我的存在
send me a notification right or my exist
请求在此处的某个时间点执行
requests is executed here at a point
删除操作发生后，文件不会
after the delete happen the file doesn't
存在，所以现在调用返回true
exist and so now the call returns true
和
and
不，实际上监视表项是
no well actually a watch table entry is
进去了，但是我们不在乎，所以它是
entered but we don't care right so it's
很重要的一点是，这些权利是
quite important that the rights are
已排序，该读取发生在
sequenced and that reads happen at
权利之间的确定点，是的，很好
definite points between rights yes well
好的，是的，这就是存在的地方
okay so yes so this is where the exists
执行时，文件不存在于
is executed the file doesn't exist at
此点存在，返回FALSE，我们不
this point exists returns false we don't
等等，我们转到一个，我们创建文件，然后
wait we go to one we create the file and
回来，我们确实在这里安装了一块手表，
return we did install a watch here that
手表会被触发，它不会
watch will be triggered it doesn't
真的很重要因为我们并不是真的
really matter because we're not really
在等它，但是手表会在
waiting for it but the watch will be
由此创建的
triggered by this created
我们不是在等它，但是好的，好的
we're not waiting for it but yeah okay
所以这个文件不存在，我们去一个
so the file doesn't exist we go to one
其他人已经创建了我们的文件
somebody else has created the file we
尝试创建失败的文件
try to create the file that fails we
再装一块手表，它就坏了
install another watch and it's a dis
注意，我们不是在等待，所以这就是
watch that we're not waiting for so this
路不会等待任何东西
way does not a wait for anything to
尽管这真的无关紧要，但还是会发生
happen although it doesn't really matter
在那一刻，去……不会有什么坏处。
in the moment it's not harmful to to to
早点打破这个循环，只是
break out of this loop early it's just
不管怎么说都是浪费，我们有所有的历史
wasteful anyway we've all the history
此代码在某种程度上将手表留在
this code leaves watches sort of in the
我真的不知道是什么
system and I don't really know what does
我的新手表在同一文件覆盖
my new watch on the same file override
我的旧手表我不太确定
my old watch I'm not actually sure
好的，我终于做到了这个例子和
okay I'm finally this example and the
前面的例子Suffle患上了
previous example suffle suffer from the
羊群效应我们也听到了效应
herd effect we also heard effect we
我是说我们刚才说的话
talked about I mean what we were talking
当我们在担心的时候，哦，但是
about when we were worrying about oh but
如果客户端，我将尝试在以下位置递增此值
if clients I'll try to increment this at
同一时间
the same time
天哪，那会是N的平方
gosh that's going to have N squared
复杂到需要多长时间
complexity as far as how long it takes
才能达到所有1000个客户端的此锁
to get to all thousand clients this lock
方案也会受到羊群效应的影响
scheme also suffers from the herd effect
因为如果有一千个客户
in that if there are a thousand clients
试图拿到锁，然后是金额
trying to get the lock then the amount
所需时间的长短
of time that's required to sort of grant
上千人中的每一个人的锁
the lock to each one of the thousand
客户与一千成正比
clients is proportional to a thousand
平方，因为在每次发布之后
squared because after every release all
的剩余客户端被触发
of the remaining clients get triggered
到了这只表上，剩下的所有人
by this watch all of the remaining
客户回到这里，送来一个
clients go back up here and send in a
创建，因此创建总数
create and so the total number create
我们生成的PC基本上是一个
our pcs generated is basically a
一千的平方，所以这件事
thousand squared so this suffers from
这个牛群，整个等待的牛群
this herd the whole herd of waiting
客户们正在殴打另一名动物园管理员
clients is beating on zookeeper another
它的名字是它是一个非
name for this is that it's a non
可伸缩的锁，或者是的，好的，所以
scalable lock or yeah okay and so the
纸是一笔实实在在的交易，我们将拭目以待。
paper is a real deal and we'll see it
更多，在其他系统中，很快
more and in other systems and soon
足够严重的问题结束了这篇论文
enough serious end of problems the paper
实际上是在谈论如何解决这个问题
actually talks about how to solve it
使用动物园饲养员和有趣的
using zookeeper and the interesting
问题是，祖克
thing is that Zook
它实际上有足够的表现力
it's actually expressive enough to be
能够构建更复杂的锁定方案
able to build a more complex lock scheme
不会受到这种伤害的人
that doesn't suffer from this hurt
即使是一千个客户
effect that even of a thousand clients
在等待一个客户的费用
are waiting the cost of one client
放弃一把锁和另一次获取
giving up a lock and another acquiring
它是阶数1而不是阶数n，并且
it is order 1 instead of order n and
这是因为它有点
this is the because it's a little bit
复杂这是
complex this is the pseudocode in the
第2.4节中的论文如果出现以下情况，请参见第6页
paper in section 2.4 it's on page 6 if
你想跟着走，所以这是
you want to follow along so this is and
所以这一次没有一把锁
so this time there is not a single lock
文件
file
不，是的，这只是一个名字
there's no yes it is just a name that
让我们都可以谈论同样的事情
allows us to all talk about the same
锁上了，所以这只是个名字，现在我知道了
lock so it's just a name know now I've
我拿到了锁，我能做到，我能做到
acquired the lock and I can do I can
不管是什么锁在保护你
whatever the lock was protecting you
一次可能只知道我们中的一个人
know maybe only one of us at a time
应该被允许在
should be allowed to give a lecture in
如果你想在这个演讲厅里
this lecture hall if you want to give a
在这个讲堂里讲课，你先来
lecture in this lecture hall you first
必须获取名为34100的锁
have to acquire the lock called 34 100
结果是，是的，它是个Z
the that turns out it's yes it's a Z
结点和动物园看守人，但它不喜欢任何人
node and zookeeper but it like nobody
关心它的内容，我们只是需要它
cares about its contents we just need it
为了能够就名称达成一致，
to be able to agree on a name for the
锁，这就是它的意义所在
lock that's the sense in which that's
PIYA这个看起来像是一个文件系统
piyah this it looks like a file system
但这真的是一个命名系统好吗
but it's really a naming system alright
所以第一步是我们创建一个序列
so step one is we create a sequential
文件
file
所以，是的，我们给它一个前缀名称，但是
and so yeah we give it a prefix name but
它实际上创造的是如果你知道
what it actually creates is you know if
这是第27个文件顺序文件
this is the 27th file sequential file
使用前缀F创建，您知道
created with with prefix F you know
也许我们得到的是F27或者别的什么，然后
maybe we get F 27 or something and and
在按以下顺序排序的
in the sequenced in the sequence of
写着动物园管理员是不是在工作
writes that zookeeper is it's working
通过相继的创造获得提升
through successive creates get ascending
保证上升，永不下降
guaranteed ascending never descending
在以下情况下始终按升序排列序列号
always ascending sequence numbers when
您创建了一个顺序文件，其中有
you create a sequential file there was
我从清单上漏掉的一项手术
an operation I left off from the list it
原来你可以得到一个文件列表
turns out you can get a list of files
您可以在下面获得文件列表
you can get a list of files underneath
你给出了泽诺的名字，那就是
you give the name of Zeno that's
实际上是一个包含文件的目录
actually a directory with files in it
您可以获得所有文件的列表，这些文件
you can get a list of all the files that
目前都在该目录中，所以我们
are currently in that directory so we're
我要列出我们开始的文件
gonna list the files let's start with
你知道，也许我们能拿到f星
that you know maybe list f star we get
返回一些列表，我们使用
some list back we create a file with the
系统给我们分配了一个号码，在这里我们可以
system allocated us a number here we can
看看这个数字，如果没有更低的话
look at that number if there's no lower
在这个列表中编号的文件，那么我们就赢了
numbered file in this list then we win
我们就能拿到锁
and we get the lock
所以如果我们的顺序文件是最低的
so if our sequential file is the lowest
带名称前缀编号文件我们赢了
number file with that name prefix we win
所以没有更低的数字我们已经打开了锁
so no lower number we've quired the lock
如果有的话，我们可以退货。
and we can return if there is one then
再说一次我们想要等待的是什么
again what we want to wait for then
事情是这样的，这些
what's going on is that these
正在设置按顺序编号的文件
sequentially numbered files are setting
向上移动锁的顺序
up the order in which the lock is going
授予不同的客户
to be granted to the different clients
所以如果我们不是锁定的赢家
so if we're not the winner of the lock
我们要做的就是等待
what we need to do is wait for the
以前与以下客户一起编号的客户
previously numbered with the client who
创建了先前编号的文件以
created the previously numbered file to
释放以获取，然后释放
release to acquire and then release the
锁上了，我们要解开锁
lock and we're going to release the lock
释放锁定的约定
the convention for releasing the locking
在这个系统中是为了
in this system is for
删除文件以删除您的
remove the file to remove your
顺序文件，所以我们要等待
sequential file so we want to wait for
先前编号的顺序文件
the previously numbered sequential file
被删除，然后就轮到我们了
to be deleted and then it's our turn and
我们拿到锁了，所以我们需要打电话给
we get the lock so we need to call
所以我们要说如果这个电话
exists so we're gonna say if the call
主要存在于设置观察点
exists mostly to set a watch point
所以这是你知道的下一个较低数字的文件
so it's you know next lower number file
我们想要一块手表来实现这一点
and we want to have a watch get that
文件仍然存在，我们要等待
file still exist we're gonna wait and
那就是第五步
then so that's step 5
最后我们要回到
and then finally we're gonna go back to
我们不会再次创建该文件
we're not going to create the file again
因为它已经存在了我们要去
because it already exists we're gonna go
回到列表上，是的，文件，所以
back to listing the yeah the files so
这是我刚删掉的合唱团专辑
this is a choir releases just I delete
如果我获得了锁，我会删除我的
if I acquire the lock I delete my the
我创建的带有我的号码的文件
file I created complete with my number
是
yes
为什么需要再次列出这些文件
why do you need to list the files again
这是个好问题，所以问题是
that's a good question so the question
我们拿到了我们知道的文件清单
is we got the list of files we know the
下一个较低编号的文件中有一个
next lower number file there's a
顺序文件的保证
guarantee of the sequential file
创造是，一旦提交了27份文件，
creation is that once filed 27 is
将不会创建编号较小的文件
created no file with a lower number will
曾经被创造过，所以我们现在
ever subsequently be created so we now
我知道没有别的东西可以偷偷溜进来
know nothing else could sneak in here so
下一个更低的号码怎么能把你
how could the next lower number file you
知道为什么我们需要再次上市吗？
know why why do we need to list again
我们为什么不回去等着
why don't we just go back to waiting for
同样是那个编号较低的文件
that same lower numbered file thing
布兰妮猜猜答案
Britney guess the answer
我是说这个代码的工作方式
I mean the the the way this code works
问题的答案是无论是谁
the answer to the question is whoever
是下一个地位较低的人可能
was the next lowered person might have
要么他至少拿到了锁
either acquired him at least the lock
在我们注意到或死去之前
before we noticed or have died and this
去了，这些是临时文件，抱歉
went and these are transient files sorry
或者任何他们被称为短暂的东西
or whatever they're called ephemeral
有一份短暂的文件，你甚至知道
there's an ephemeral file you know even
如果我们排在第26行的第27位
if we're 27th in line number 26 may have
在获得锁IF编号之前死亡
died before getting the lock if number
26条死亡，系统自动删除
26 dies the system automatically deletes
他们的临时文件，所以如果
their ephemeral files and so if that
现在发生了，我们需要等待号码
happened now we need to wait for number
那就是下一次了，如果都知道的话，你就知道了。
25 that is the next you know it if all
您知道的文件2到27和
files you know 2 through 27 and and
如果他们是我们的全部，我们就是27岁
we're 27 if they're all they are and
他们都在等着，如果有锁的话
they're all waiting there's a lock if if
前面的那个还没来得及死就死了
the one before is dies before getting
锁现在我们需要等待
the lock now we need to wait for the
下一个较低编号的文件不是因为
next next lower number file not because
下一个更低的是已经走了，所以
the next lower one is has gone away so
这就是为什么我们要回去重新登记
that's why we have to go back and relist
这些文件以防我们的前任在
the files in case our predecessor in the
出现的等待客户端列表
list of waiting clients turned out to
耶
die yes
如果没有比这更低编号文件
if there's no lower numbered file than
你已经获得了绝对的锁
you have acquired the lock absolutely
是的，这怎么就不会受到
yes how does this not suffer from the
羊群效应假设我们有一千
herd effect suppose we have a thousand
正在等待的客户端和当前客户端
clients waiting and currently client
从最初的五百多美元中脱颖而出
made through the first five hundred and
客户端500每隔一个时间持有锁
client five hundred holds the lock every
客户等待每个客户都坐着
client waiting every client is sitting
在这里等待一个事件，但只有
here waiting for an event but only the
创建了五百个文件的客户端
client that created file five hundred
还有一个他在等待的幻觉
and one he's waiting for the vision of
提交五百份，所以每个人都在等着
file five hundred so everybody's waiting
下一个较低的数字，也就是5
for the next lower number so five
百人在等49929
hundred is waiting for 499 twenty nine
九个人，但是每个人都在等着
nine but everybody everybody's waiting
只有一个文件，当我释放
for just one file when I release the
锁定只有一个客户
lock there's only one other client the
下一个编号较高的客户端，即
next higher numbered client that's
在等我的文件，所以当我释放的时候
waiting for my file so when I release
锁定一个客户端将收到通知
the lock one client gets a notification
一个客户端返回并列出文件
one client goes back and lists the files
一个客户端和一个客户端现在具有
one client and one client now has the
锁定，所以这种费用你不知道
lock so the sort of expense you know no
重要的是有多少客户端是
matter how many clients that are the
每个版本中的一个版本的费用，以及
expense of one of each release and
Acquisition是我们固定数量的PC
acquire is a constant number of our PCs
发行的费用在哪里？
where's the expense of a release and
这里得到的是每一个人
acquire here is that every single
通知正在等待的客户端，并且每隔
waiting client is notified and every
其中一个发送写入请求
single one of them sends a write request
而不是将创建请求发送到ZooKeeper
than the create request into zookeeper
哦，你可以自由地去喝杯咖啡
oh you're free to get a cup of coffee
是的，我是说，这是你知道的
yeah I mean this is you know what the
编程接口看起来不是
programming interface looks like is not
我们的生意，但这不是和
our business but this is either and
对于什么有两种选择
there's there's two options for what
这实际上意味着
this actually means as far as what the
程序看起来像是有一些
program looks like one is there's some
实际上处于同步状态的线程
thread that's actually in a synchronous
等等，它已经进行了一个函数调用，说明
wait it's made a function call saying
请获取此锁和
please acquire this lock and the
函数HOLD不会返回，直到
function hold doesn't return until the
最终获取的锁或
locks finally acquired or the
通知返回的内容要多得多
notification comes back of much more
复杂的界面将是一个
sophisticated interface would being one
在这种情况下，您可以发出请求，而不是
in which you fire off requests a
动物园管理员，不要再等了
zookeeper and don't wait and then
分开来看，有一些方式
separately there's some way of seeing
好吧，你信守诺言
well as you keep your said anything
最近还是我有一些围棋的例行公事
recently or I have some go routine whose
工作就是等待下一份工作
job it is just wait for the next
不管是动物园管理员送来的什么
whatever it is from zookeeper in the
同样的感觉，你可能会读到申请表
same sense that you might read the apply
频道和各式各样的
Channel and just all kinds of
有趣的事情会在申请中出现
interesting stuff comes up on the apply
所以这是一种更有可能的方式
channel so that's a more likely way to
构建这个，但是，是的，你完全是
structure this but yeah you're totally
不管是通过穿线，还是通过某种
either through threading or some sort of
事件驱动的事情你可以做一些事情
event-driven thing you can do something
否则在你等待的时候是的是的或者如果
else while you're waiting yes yes or if
在我之前的那个人也没有死
the person before me has neither died
也没有公布，这是我面前的一份文件
nor released it's a file before me
存在，这意味着要么该客户端
exists that means either that client is
还活着，还在等待
still alive and still waiting for the
锁上或仍然活着并握住锁
lock or still alive and holds the lock
我们真的不知道
we don't really know
只要客户端500
it does it as long as that client 500
如果此存在失败，则仍处于活动状态
still live if if this exists fails that
意味着两件事中的一件，要么是我的
means one of two things either my
前任持有锁并且是
predecessor held the lock and is
释放它并删除他们的文件或我的
released it and deleted their file or my
前辈没有持有他们的锁
predecessor didn't hold the lock they
已退出，动物园管理员删除了他们的文件
exited and zookeeper deleted their file
因为这是一个短暂的文件，所以
because it was an ephemeral file so
从这件事中走出来有两个原因
there's two reasons to come out of this
才能减掉他的一两个体重
to come out of his weight or four they
存在是为了返回假，这就是为什么我们
exist to return false and that's why we
你得喜欢我们检查你的一切
have to like we check everything you
我知道你真的不知道
know you really don't know what the
情况是在EXISTS完成之后
situation is after the exists completes
那可能是，对，也许是那样
that might that yeah maybe maybe that
可能需要工作，这听起来
could need to work that sounds
合理的
reasonable
并且它保留了可伸缩的
and it preserves the sort of scalable
每个人都需要这个和那个的性质
nature of this and that each require
版本仅涉及几个客户端两个
release only involves a few clients two
客户端
clients
好的，实际上我喜欢这个式样。
alright this pattern to me actually
第一次看到这个图案完全是
first saw this pattern a totally
不同的上下文和可伸缩的锁
different context and scalable locks for
线程系统，我把这一端放在这里
threading systems I go this end in for
在世界上的大多数地方，这被称为天平
most of the world this is called a scale
一把锁的
of a lock
我发现它是那些有趣的东西之一
I find it one of those interesting
我现在所见过的建筑
constructions I've ever seen now and so
好像我印象深刻的是动物园管理员
like I'm impressed that zookeeper is
能够表达它，而且它是一个有价值的
able to express it and it's a valuable
我说过我有一点
construct having said that I'm a little
有点不知所措，为什么动物园管理员会问为什么
bit at sea about why zookeeper about why
报纸上谈到的都是锁
the paper talks about locks at all
因为这些锁这些锁不是
because these locks these locks are not
就像穿线锁一样，因为在
like threading locks and go because in
线程没有线程的概念
threading there's no notion of threads
失败至少在你不想要他们的时候
failing at least if you don't want them
可能没有任何关于
there to be there's no notions of
线条就像是随机死亡的
threads just sort of randomly dying and
去吧，所以你唯一能做的就是
go and so really the only thing you're
从互斥体中走出来真的是
getting out of a mutex it's really the
当你使用它的时候，如果你用它的话
case and go that when you use it if
每个人都正确使用互斥锁你是
everybody uses mutexes correctly you are
获取序列的原子性
getting atomicity for the sequence of
操作的互斥锁内的操作，您可以在互斥锁中
operations inside the mutex that you
我知道如果你拿出一把锁
know if you take out a lock and go and
你要做47种不同的读写
you do 47 different read and write a lot
，然后释放锁。
of variables and then release the lock
如果每个人都遵循那个锁
if everybody follows that locking
策略没人会看到
strategy nobody's ever going to see some
一种奇怪的中间版本
sort of weird intermediate version of
截止到一半的数据你是
the data as of halfway through you're
正确地更新它只会让事情变得
updating it right just makes things
原子无参数这些锁不是
atomic no argument these locks aren't
真的很喜欢，因为如果客户
really like that because if the client
持有锁的那个失败了，它只是
that holds the lock fails it just
释放锁，其他人就可以
releases the lock and somebody else can
把锁拿起来，这样它就不会
pick up the lock so it does not
保证原子性，因为您可以获得
guarantee atomicity because you can get
部分故障与分布式系统
partial failures and distributed systems
在那里你不会真的偏袒
where you don't really get partial
普通线程代码的失败，因此如果
failures of ordinary threaded code so if
现在的锁持有者有锁，
the current lock holder had the lock and
需要更新一大堆东西
needed to update a whole bunch of things
它们以前被锁保护过
that were protected by that lock before
放飞，只走了一半
releasing and only got halfway through
更新了这些东西，然后崩溃了
updating this stuff and then crashed
然后锁就会被释放你会
then the lock will get released you'll
拿到锁，但当你去看的时候
get the lock and yet when you go to look
在数据上它是垃圾，因为它是
at the data it's garbage because it's
不管它是什么随机的种子
just whatever random seed it was in the
中间
middle of
已更新，因此这些锁不会
updated so there's these locks don't by
它们本身提供了相同的原子性
themselves provide the same atomicity
保证线程锁可以这样做，因此
guarantee that threading locks do and so
我们在某种程度上可以想象
we're sort of left to imagine for
我们靠报纸或者为什么你会
ourselves by the paper or why you would
想要使用它们，或者为什么要使用这种类型
want to use them or why this is the sort
中的一些主要示例
of some of the main examples in the
所以我想如果你用像这样的锁
paper so I think if you use locks like
然后，您可以在分布式的
this then you sort in a distributed
系统，那么您有两个常规选项
system then you have two general options
一是每个获得锁的人都有
one is everybody who acquires a lock has
准备好清理一些
to be prepared to clean up from some
以前的灾难权利，所以您可以获得
previous disaster right so you acquire
此锁可查看您尝试的数据
this lock you look at the data you try
去找出天哪，如果以前的主人
to figure out gosh if the previous owner
一大堆坠毁的东西
of a lot crashed
你知道当我在看数据的时候
you know when I'm looking at the data
你知道我怎么才能把数据修改成
you know how can I fix the data to make
我怎么才能决定之前的
up how can I decide if the previous
车主崩溃了，我该怎么修理呢？
owner crashed and what do I do to fix up
然后你就可以玩这个游戏了
the data and you can play that game
特别是如果约定是你
especially if the convention is that you
始终按特定顺序更新
always update in a particular sequence
你也许能检测到它的位置
you may be able to detect where in that
前一个托架崩溃的顺序
sequence the previous holder crashed
假设他们坠毁了，但那是一个你
assuming they crashed but it's a you
我知道这是一场棘手的比赛
know it's a tricky game the requires
想出一种你不需要的东西
thought of a kind you don't need for
就像线程锁定，嗯，另一个原因
like thread locking um the other reason
也许这些锁是有意义的，如果
maybe these locks would make sense is if
有一种软锁可以保护
there's sort of soft locks protecting
一些真正无关紧要的事情
something that doesn't really matter
例如，如果您正在运行
so for example if you're running
MapReduce作业地图任务减少任务
MapReduce jobs map tasks reduce tasks
你可以用这种锁来做
you could use this kind of lock to make
当然，只有一项任务，只有一名工人
sure only one task only one worker
执行了每项任务，所以工作人员将运行
executed each task so workers gonna run
测试37它获得任务37的锁
test 37 it gets the lock for task 37
Execute它将其标记为已执行，并且
execute it marks it as executed and
以不生产的方式很好地释放它
releases it well the way not produce
它实际上是用来证明
works it's actually proof against
不管怎么说，撞车的工人，所以如果你抓住一个
crashed workers anyway so if you grab a
锁住了，然后你在半路上撞车了
lock and you crash halfway through your
MapReduce工作，那么下一个人会是什么呢
MapReduce job so what the next person
谁拿到了你知道的锁，因为你的
who gets the lock you know because your
当您崩溃时，锁将被释放
lock will be released when you crash the
拿到它的下一个版本将会看到您
next version who gets it will see you
没有完成任务，只有我们
didn't finish the task and just we
执行它，这就不是问题了
execute it and it's just not a problem
由于MapReduce的定义方式
because of the way MapReduce is defined
所以你可以用这些锁或者一些
so you could use these locks or some
一种软锁的东西，尽管不管怎样
kind of soft lock thing although anyway
你知道也许另一件事就是
and you know maybe the other thing which
我们应该考虑的是一些
we should be thinking about is that some
此版本的
version of this
被用来做像选举大师这样的事情
be used to do things like elect a master
但如果我们真正在这里做的是
but if what we're really doing here is
选举一位大师，你知道我们可以用
electing a master you know we could use
代码很像这样，那样就会
code much like this and that would
可能是个合理的方法是的
probably be a reasonable approach yeah
哦，好的，那么采摘
oh yeah yeah yeah so the picking of
纸质谈话，记住课文中的内容
paper talk that remember the text in the
报纸Ware说它将删除
paper were says it's going to delete the
准备好文件，然后做一堆
ready file and then do a bunch of
更新文件，然后重新创建
updates to files and then recreate the
准备好的文件，这将是一个
ready file that would that is a
一种奇妙的侦测方式
fantastic way of sort of detecting and
应对这样一种可能性，即
coping with the possibility that the
持有的上一个锁或上一个锁
previous lock held or the previous
师父或它在半路上坠毁的任何人
master or whoever it is crashed halfway
因为天哪，准备好的文件里有
through because gosh the ready file has
永不创建
never be created
伊尼戈计划，是的，很遗憾，那是
Inigo program yeah sadly that is
有可能，你要么知道，要么好的，所以
possible and you know either okay so the
问题不是关于动物园管理员，而是
question is nothing about zookeeper but
如果您正在编写线程化代码并执行
if you're writing threaded code and go a
线程获取锁是否会崩溃
thread acquires a lock could it crash
在中途握住锁的同时
while holding the lock halfway through
不管它应该做什么
whatever stuff it's supposed to be doing
同时拿着一把锁，答案是
while holding a lock and the answer is
是的，实际上有很多方法
yes actually there are there are ways
使单个线程崩溃并离开
for an individual thread to crash and go
哦，我忘了他们在哪里，也许会分开
oh I forget where they are maybe divide
通过零，某些恐慌不管怎样，你能做的
by zero certain panics anyway you can do
它和我关于如何思考的建议
it and my advice about how to think
关于这一点的是，这个项目现在是
about that is that the program is now
坏了，你必须杀了它，因为
broken and you've got to kill it because
在线程化代码中，关于
in threaded code the way the thing about
锁是指在持有锁的同时，
locks is that while the lock is held the
数据中的不变量并非如此
invariants in the data don't hold so
如果锁被锁住了，我们就不能继续前进了
there's no way to proceed if the lock
霍尔德坠毁了，没有安全的方法可以
holder crashes there's no safe way to
继续，因为你所知道的一切都是
proceed because all you know is whatever
不变量是锁是
the invariants were that the lock was
保护不再持有某某某某
protecting no longer hold so and so and
如果您确实想继续，您必须
if you do want to proceed you have to
将锁标记为持有，这样就不会
leave the lock marked as held so that no
其他人永远都不会得到它
one else will ever be able to acquire it
你知道除非你有一些聪明的
and you know unless you have some clever
这几乎就是你所拥有的方式
idea that's pretty much the way you have
在线程化程序中考虑它
to think about it in a threaded program
因为这是一种
because that's kind of the style with
哪些人编写线程锁
which people write threaded lock
程序，如果你超级聪明的话
programs if you're super clever you
可以玩同样的把戏，比如
could play the same kinds of tricks like
这个准备好的旗帜戏法现在太棒了
this ready flag trick now it's super
硬着头皮，因为内存模型
hard and go because the memory model
他说你没有什么可以依靠的
says there is nothing you can count on
除非之前发生过
except if there's a happens before
所以如果你玩这个游戏
relationship so if you play this game of
编写更改一些变量，然后
writing changing some variables and then
设置完成标志并不意味着
setting a done flag that doesn't mean
什么都行，除非你松开一把锁
anything unless you release a lock and
其他人获得了锁，并且只有
somebody else acquires a lock and only
那我们还能说些什么吗？
then can anything be said about the
按哪种顺序，甚至是按哪种顺序
order in which or in even whether the
更新会发生，所以这非常非常困难
updates happen so this is very very hard
它非常努力，要从一场灾难中恢复过来
it rivairy hard and go to recover from a
持有锁的线程崩溃
crash of a thread that holds the lock
这里可能更有可能
here is maybe a little more possible
好的，我想说的就这些。
okay okay okay that's all I want to talk
关于动物园管理员
about with zoo keeper
只有两件高价出价一件是
it's just two pieces of high bid one is
在这些高中生的聪明点子上
at these clever ideas for high
通过从任何复制副本读取来提高性能
performance by reading from any replica
但是他们牺牲了一点
but the they sacrifice a bit of
一致性和其他有趣的
consistency and the other interesting
乏味的是带回家的是
thing uninteresting take-home is that
他们制定了这个API，真的
they worked out this API that really
让它们成为一种通用的类型
does let them be a general-purpose sort
协调服务的一种方式
of coordination service in a way that
更简单的方案，如PUT、GET接口
simpler schemes like put get interfaces
只是做不到，所以他们想出了一套
just can't do so they worked out a set
一系列函数，使您可以执行以下操作
of functions here that allows you to do
写小事务和写小事务之类的事情
things like write mini transactions and
自己造锁，一切都能正常工作
build your own locks and it all works
虽然需要照顾，但现在好了，我
out although requires care okay now I
我想看看今天的报纸，它是
want to turn to today's paper which is
破解我们为什么要读一本
crack the the reason why we're reading a
破解纸有几个原因其中一个是
crack paper it's a couple reasons one is
是它为以下对象进行复制
is that it's it does replication for
容错，正如我们将看到的
fault tolerance and as we'll see the
你从裂缝中获得的属性或者它的
properties you get out of crack or its
前驱链复制是非常重要的
predecessor chain replication are very
在有趣的方面不同于
different in interesting ways from the
您从系统中获得的属性，如
properties you get out of a system like
木筏，所以我现在要讲的是
raft and so I'm actually going to talk
所以可卡因在某种程度上是一种
about so crack is sort of an
对较旧的方案进行优化，该方案称为
optimization to an older scheme called
链复制链复制
chain replication chain replications
实际上相当频繁地用在
actually fairly frequently used in the
现实世界里有一堆系统
real world there's a bunch of systems
使用它的人
that use it
裂缝是对它的优化
crack is an optimization to it that
实际上做了一个类似的把戏-
actually does a similar trick -
动物园管理员在那里它试图增加
zookeeper where it's trying to increase
通过允许读取两次来消除吞吐量
weed throughput by allowing reads to two
复制到任何副本，这样您就可以
replicas to any replicas so that you get
你知道复制品的数量因素
you know number of replicas factor of
提高了读取性能
increase in the read performance the
可卡因的有趣之处在于它
interesting thing about crack is that it
是不是在保存的同时
does that while preserving
线性化能力
linearise ability
不像你知道的动物园管理员
unlike zookeeper which you know it
似乎是为了能够阅读
seemed like in order to be able to read
从他们不得不牺牲的任何复制品中
from any replica they had to sacrifice
清新，因此流鼻涕
freshness and therefore snot
可线性化的裂缝实际上设法
linearizable crack actually manages to
在以下情况下从任何复制副本执行这些读取
do these reads from any replica while
保持强烈的一致性，我只是
preserving strong consistency I'm just
很有趣，好的，所以首先我想
pretty interesting okay so first I want
谈论较旧的系统链
to talk about the older system chain
复制青少年复制是它的
replication teen replication is a it's
这只是一个方案，因为你有多个
just a scheme for you have multiple
您要确保它们都是副本的副本
copies you want to make sure they all
看到了相同的权利序列，所以它是
seen the same sequence of right so it's
像是一个非常熟悉的基本概念，但它
like a very familiar basic idea but it's
一个不同的拓扑，然后是筏子，因此
a different topology then raft so the
想法是有一个服务器链
idea is that there's a chain of servers
和链式复制，第一个
and chain replication and the first one
被称为最前面的，最后一个被称为
is called the head last one's called the
当右手进入时尾部，当客户端
tail when a right comes in when a client
想写点什么，比如某个客户
wants to write something say some client
它总是把奥尔布赖特的被送到
it sends always Albright's get sent to
磁头更新它的或
the head the head updates its or
替换其数据的当前副本
replaces its current copy of the data
客户写信给你这样你就可以
that the clients writing so you can
想象一下，你要把密钥值存储起来，这样你
imagine be go put key value store so you
如果每个人都是从你开始的
know if everybody started out with you
了解数据的a版和以下版本
know version a of the data and under
头部处理时的链复制
chain replication when the head process
是正确的，也许我们在写
is the right and maybe we're writing
价值B，你知道头部只是取代了
value B you know the head just replaces
A带B，向下传右
its a with a B and passes the right down
链，因为每个节点都看到它的右边
the chain as each node sees the right it
替换覆盖其拷贝的数据
replaces over writes its copy the data
当权限获得时的新数据
the new data when the right gets the
尾部将回复发送回
tail the tail sends the reply back to
客户说我们完成了你的
the client saying we completed your
正确的
right
这就是权利工作的内容，如果一个客户
that's how rights work reads if a client
想要执行它将读取发送到的读取
wants to do a read it sends the read to
尾部表示尾部的读取请求
the tail the read request of the tail
它的尾巴就会从它的
and the tail just answers out of its
当前状态，所以如果我们要求这样做
current state so if we ask for this
不管这个物体是什么，它的尾巴
whatever this object was the tail which
我希望现在的价值是杂草
is I hope current values be weeds are a
好得多，更简单
good deal simpler
好的，那么它应该考虑一下
okay so it should think for a moment
比如为什么要链式复制
like why to chain chain replication so
这不是破解，只是为了澄清这一点
this is not crack just to be clear this
链复制是链复制吗
is chain replication chain replication
是可以线性化的，你知道，在不存在的情况下
is linearizable you know in the absence
失败的原因是我们
of failures what's going on is that we
从本质上讲，我可以把它看作是真正意义上的
can essentially view it as really than
思考的目的是为了
the purposes of thinking about
一致性只有这一台服务器
consistency it's just this one server
服务器会看到所有权限，并且它
the server sees all the rights and it
查看所有读取并对其进行处理
sees all the reads and process them one
一次，你知道一次阅读只会
at a time and you know a read will just
查看写入的最新值，并
see the latest value that's written and
这几乎就是它的全部内容。
that's pretty much all there is to it
从这个角度看，如果有
from the point of view look if there's
没有崩溃，一致性是什么样子
no crashes what the consistency is like
非常简单的故障恢复
pretty simple the failure recovery the a
连锁店背后的很多理由
lot of the rationale behind chain
复制是一组状态
replication is that the set of states
你可以看到在失败之后
you can see when after there's a failure
是相对受限的，因为
is relatively constrained because of
这是一种非常有规律的模式，它是如何
this very regular pattern with how the
写入被传播，并且处于较高水平
writes get propagated and at a high
水平是怎么回事，有没有
level what's going on is that any
任何速率的提交写入
committed write that is any rate that
可能已经向客户确认了
could have been acknowledged to a client
发送到书写客户端，或者以任何速率
to the writing client or any rate that
可能是在一次阅读中暴露的
could have been exposed in a read
那是不会的，那两个都不会
that'll neither of those will ever
除非写入到达
happen unless that write reached the
尾巴才能到达尾巴
tail in order for it to reach the tail
它必须在过程中经过它们
it had to a pass through them in process
链中的每一个节点，所以我们
by every single node in the chain so we
要知道如果我们曾经接触过写作
know that if we ever exposed to write
曾经确认过的写入是否将其用于
ever acknowledged write ever use it to a
读取，这意味着
read that means every single node in the
尾巴一定知道我们不知道的权利
tail must know about that right we don't
把这些情况弄清楚，比如如果你要打电话给
get these situations like if you'll call
图7图8和RAF纸张
figure seven figure eight and RAF paper
在那里你可以让人毛骨悚然
where you can have just hair-raising
复杂性以及它们之间的不同之处
complexity and how the different
如果这里发生崩溃，复制件就会不同
replicas differ if there's a crash here
你知道它要么是承诺的，要么就是
you know either that it is committed or
它在坠机前应该会达到一些
it before the crash should reach some
这一点，在那点之后就无处可去了
point and nowhere after that point
因为权利的进步
because the progress of rights has
始终菜单，因此提交的权限是
always menu so committed rights are
如果没有权利，到处都知道
always known everywhere if a right isn't
这意味着在此之前
committed that means that before
不管是什么撞车事件扰乱了
whatever crash it was that disturb the
系统进入某一特定区域的速率
system the rate of got into a certain
指向该点之前的任何地方，然后
point everywhere before that point and
此后无处可寻
nowhere after
我要指出的是，实际上只有两个设置
point there's really the only two setups
在较高级别上，故障恢复是
and at a high level failure recovery is
如果头部发生故障，也相对简单
relatively simple also if the head fails
然后到下一次的第一次近似值
then to a first approximation the next
节点可以简单地接管他的头
node can simply take over his head and
没有其他事情需要做了，因为
nothing else needs to get done because
任何让它走到最远的速度
any rate that made it as far as the
第二个节点，而它是头部
second node while it was the head that
失败了，所以权利会继续下去
failed so that right will keep on going
我们会承诺如果有一个比率
and we'll commit if there's a rate that
在撞车前撞到了头部，但是
made it to the head before a crash but
头部没有很好地向前推进，那是
the head didn't forward it well that's
绝对没有承诺没人知道
definitely not committed nobody knows
关于这件事，我们绝对没有派
about it and we definitely didn't send
这是对写作的承认
it an acknowledgment to the writing
客户端，因为写入没有写下来
client because the write didn't get down
在这里，所以我们没有义务做任何事情
here so we're not obliged to do anything
关于一次写入，它只达到了崩溃
about a write it only reached a crashed
在它失败之前的头我可能是
head before it failed I may be the
我们犯了罪的客户，但你不知道
client where we sinned but you know not
我们的问题是如果故事失败了
our problem if the tale fails it's
实际上非常类似的故事失败了
actually very similar the tale fails the
下一个节点可以直接接管，因为
next node can directly take over because
故事所知道的一切然后下一步
everything the tale knew then next the
节点之前的节点也知道，因为
node just before it also knows because
这个故事只从节点听到消息
the tale only hears things from the node
就在它之前，它有一点
just before it and it's a little bit
中间节点的联合体出现故障
complex of an intermediate node fails
但基本上需要做的是
but basically what needs to be done is
我们需要把它从链子上扔掉
we need to drop it from the chain and
现在可能有它拥有的权利
now there may be rights that it had
收到下一个节点尚未
received that the next node hasn't
还没收到，所以如果我们丢了一张纸条
received yet and so if we drop a note
在链之外，前辈可以
out of the chain the predecessor may
需要将最近的权限重新发送给
need to resend recent rights to the to
它的新继承权，也就是
its new successor right that's the
一言以蔽之，这就是为什么
recovery in a nutshell that's for why
这个结构为什么不是这个而是这个
this construction why this instead of
一些其他的东西，比如为什么这一节是
something else like why this verse is
包装，例如表演
wrapped for example the performance
原因是如果你还记得我们在木筏上
reason is that in raft if you recall we
你知道如果我们有一个领袖和一群
you know if we have a leader and a bunch
你们中的一些人知道一些复制品
of you know some number of replicas
对领队来说，它不是在一个
right with the leader it's not in a
链子我们有这些复制品都是
chain we got these the replicas are all
直接由领导喂食，所以如果一个
directly fed by the leader so if a
客户端权限进入或客户端读取
client right comes in or a client read
就此而言，领导人必须
for that matter the the leader has to
将其自身发送到每个复制件
send it itself to each of the replicas
而在链复制中，领先者
whereas in chain replication the leader
头上只需要做一次
on the head only has to do once and
网络上的这些美分实际上是
these cents on the network are actually
相当昂贵，所以这意味着
reasonably expensive and so that means
筏头上的负载量将会是
the load on a raft leader is going to be
高于链条上的负荷
higher than the load on a chain
复制领先者，这意味着
replication leader and so that means
你知道的客户数量
that you know as the number of client
您每秒收到的请求数
requests per second that you're getting
从客户那里升起的救生筏领袖将
from clients goes up a raft leader will
达到了极限，就不能再得到
hit a limit and stop being able to get
比链式复制更快
faster sooner than a chain replication
头部，因为它做的工作比
head because it's doing more work than
链复制还有另一个
the chain replication had another
链之间有趣的区别
interesting difference between chain
复制和木筏是芦苇
replication and raft is that the reeds
在木筏上也都要求
in raft are all also required to be
由领导者看到的领导者处理
processed by the leaders the leader sees
来自客户端的每个请求
every single request from clients
这里在哪里？头看到每个人
where's here the head sees everybody
看到所有权利，但只有尾巴看到
sees all the rights but only a tail sees
芦苇请求，因此可能会有一个
the reed requests so there may be an
负载在某种程度上
extent to which the load is sort of
头部和尾部分开
split between the head and the tail
而不是集中在领导者身上
rather than concentrated in the leader
而且就像我之前提到的
and and as I mentioned before the
故障不同类型的分析
failure different sort of analysis
需要考虑不同的
required to think about different
故障场景要简单得多
failure scenarios is a good deal simpler
和链式复制，而不是
and chain replication than it is and
木筏和作为一个很大的动力，因为
raft and as a big motivation because
这东西很难弄对，是的。
it's hard to get this stuff correct yes
是的，所以如果故事失败了，但它
yeah so if the tale fails but its
前任已经看到了一项权利，即
predecessor had seen a right that the
当时的故事还没有看到
tale hadn't seen then the failure of
黑尔基本上承诺了这一权利
that Hale basically commits that right
现在是承诺的，因为它已经到了
is now committed because it's reached
新故事，这样他就可以回应
the new tale and so he could respond to
客户可能不会，因为它
the client it probably won't because it
你知道它不是一条尾巴
you know it wasn't a tail when it
接收到权利，因此客户端可以
received the right and so the client may
重新发送右边，那太糟糕了，
resend the right and that's too bad and
所以我们需要抑制重复
so we need duplicate suppression
可能是在头部，基本上所有的
probably at the head basically all the
系统正在讨论的是Required In
systems were talking about require in
除了其他一切压制之外
addition to everything else suppression
重复客户端请求的百分比是粉红色
of duplicate client requests yes pink
你想知道你想知道的是谁
psyche setting in you want to know who
做出关于如何做到这一点的决定
makes the decisions about how to that's
一个悬而未决的问题这个问题是
a outstanding question the question is
或者稍微改变一下问题的表达方式，如果
or rephrase the question a bit if
有一个失败，就像或者假设
there's a failure like or suppose the
第二个节点停止能够与
second node stops being able to talk to
头能不能这第二个节点只取
the head can this second node just take
它能自己决定吗，天哪
over can it decide for itself gosh the
头似乎在想，我要
head seems to thought away I'm gonna
接管他的头，告诉客户
take over his head and tell clients to
跟我说话而不是跟老头子说话
talk to me instead of the old head but
你觉得这不像是个计划吗
what do you think that's not like a plan
带着我们通常做的假设
with the usual assumptions we make about
网络是如何运作的，这是一个秘诀
how the network behaves that's a recipe
如果你真的这么做的话你的大脑就会分裂
for split brain right if you do exactly
我说这些话当然是因为
what I said because of course what
真正发生的是那个眼神
really happened was that look the
网络在此出现故障，机头完全故障
network failed here the head is totally
活着，头认为它的继任者
alive and the head thinks its successor
已经死了，你知道继任者
has died you know the successors
实际上它还活着，它认为它的头
actually alive it thinks the head has
死了，他们都说，天哪
died and they both say well gosh that
另一个服务器似乎死了，我是
other server seems to have died I'm
会接手，然后头就会
gonna take over and the head is gonna
说，哦，我只会是一个唯一的复制品，而我
say oh I'll just be a sole replica and I
你知道，扮演头部和尾巴的角色
you know act as the head and the tail
因为睡觉的变化似乎
because the rest of the change seems to
已经走了，然后我来做
have gone away and second I'll do the
同样的事情，现在我们有两个
same thing and now we have two
独立的大脑分裂版本
independent split brain versions of the
数据将逐渐从
data which will gradually get out of
同步，因此此构造不是证明
sync so this construction is not proof
针对网络分区，并且没有
against network partition and has not
没有针对分裂的防御措施
does not have a defense against split
大脑，这在实践中意味着
brain and what that means in practice is
如果它不能自己使用，就像
if it cannot be used by itself it's like
在我们背后有一件很有帮助的事情
a helpful thing to have in our back
口袋里，但它不是完整的
pocket but it's not a complete
复制的故事，所以这是非常重要的
replication story so it's it's very
通常使用，但它用在这个
commonly used but it's used in this
以一种风格化的方式，总有一种
stylized way in which there's always an
外部权威，你知道的，不是这个
external Authority you know not not this
决定谁是那种人的链条
chain that decides who's that sort of
打电话给谁还活着，谁
makes a call on who's alive and who's
并确保每个人都同意一个
dead and make sure everybody agrees on a
关于谁构成的单一故事
single story about who constitutes the
改变，永远不会有任何分歧
change there's never any disagreement
有些人认为变化是这个不
some people think the change is this no
一些人认为链条就是这个
and some people think the chain is this
其他节点，通常是什么
other node so what's that's usually
作为配置管理器调用，并且
called as a configuration manager and
它的工作就是监视活跃度和
its job is just a monitor aliveness and
每次它看到所有服务器中的
every time it sees of all the servers
每次伊希斯每次
every time Isis every time the
配置管理器认为
configuration manager thinks the
服务器死了，它发出了一个新的
server's dead it sends out a new
配置，在该配置中，您知道
configuration in which you know that
这条链有了新的定义
this chain has a new definition had
不管尾巴是什么，那是什么服务器
whatever tail and that's server that the
配置管理器认为可以
configuration manager thinks is that may
或者可能没有死，但我们不在乎
or may not be dead but we don't care
因为每个人都必须遵守
because everybody is required to follow
然后您的配置
then your configuration
所以不可能有任何分歧
and so there can't be any disagreement
因为只有一个政党
because there's only one party making
这些决定不会有异议
these decisions not going to disagree
当然，有了它自己，你怎么做一个
with itself of course how do you make a
具有容错能力的服务
service that's fault tolerant and
不会与自己意见相左，但也不会
doesn't disagree with itself but doesn't
患有脑裂，如果有
suffer from split brain if there's
网络分区和答案
network partitions and the answer to
也就是说，配置管理器
that is that the configuration manager
通常用愤怒或长袍或者在
usually uses wrath or paxos or in the
一名优秀的动物园饲养员本身就是一名动物饲养员
case of crack zookeeper which itself of
球场是建在木筏上的，所以
course is built on a raft like scheme so
所以你要按照通常的完整设置
so you to the usual complete set up in
您的数据中心是不是您拥有
your data center is it you have a
配置管理器，这是它所基于的
configuration manager it's it's based on
或者在政治行动委员会之后或者其他什么，所以这是错的
or after PACs or whatever so it's fault
宽容，不受分裂之苦
tolerant and does not suffer from split
大脑，然后你拆分你的数据
brain and then you split up your data
一大堆零钱，如果你知道房间的话
over a bunch of change if you know room
里面有一千台服务器，而你
with a thousand servers in it and you
你知道A链吗？你知道它是
have you know chain a you know it's
这些服务器或配置
these servers or the configuration
经理决定更改应
manager decides that the change should
看起来a链是由一号服务器组成的
look like chain a is made of server one
服务器到服务器的三条链是你知道的
server to server three chain be you know
用于服务器5和6的服务器，无论是什么服务器和
server for server 5 over 6 whatever and
它告诉所有人这份名单上的人
it tells everybody this whole list it's
所有客户端都知道所有服务器
all the clients know all the servers
了解和个别服务器的意见
know and the individual servers opinions
关于其他服务器是否处于活动状态或
about whether other servers are alive or
死人完全不是这里也不是那里
dead are totally neither here nor there
如果这台服务器真的死了，那么
if this server really does die then then
头部需要不断地尝试
the head is required to keep trying
直到我猜到一个新的
indefinitely until I guess a new
配置中的配置
configuration from the configuration
不允许经理做出决定
manager not allowed to make decisions
关于谁活着，谁死了是什么
about who's alive and who's dead what's
那
that
哦，孩子，你有一个严重的问题，所以
oh boy you've got a serious problem so
这就是为什么你用RAFT复制
that's why you replicated using raft
确保不同的复制副本处于打开状态
make sure the different replicas are on
不同的电源供应整个工程
different power supplies the whole works
但这是我建的这个建筑
but this this construction I've set up
在这里，这是非常常见的，这就是为什么
here it's extremely common and it's how
旨在使用链复制
chain replication is intended to be used
如何使用裂缝，以及
how cracks intend to be used and the
其逻辑是需要类似链
logic of it is that like chain require
复制，如果您不必担心的话
replication if you don't have to worry
关于分区和分裂大脑，你可以
about partition and split brain you can
建造速度非常快，效率非常高
build very high speed efficient
使用链的复制系统
replication systems using chain
例如复制，因此这些
replication for example so these
您知道的个人数据复制和
individual you know data replication and
我们正在将数据分成多个链
we're sharding the data over many chains
单独地，这些链可以是
individually this these chains can be
建造得恰好是最高效的
built to be just the most efficient
针对特定类型事物的方案
scheme for the particular kind of thing
你正在复制的你可能会读到
that you're replicating you may read
重，右，重，不管是什么，但是我们不
heavy right heavy whatever but we don't
我不得不过于担心分区问题
have to worry too much about partitions
然后所有的担忧都会集中起来
and then all that worry is concentrated
在可靠的非分裂大脑中
in the reliable non split-brain
配置管理器
configuration manager
好的，那么你的问题是我们为什么
okay so your question is why are we
此处使用链复制，而不是
using chain replication here instead of
木筏好的，所以这就像是完全
raft okay so it's like a totally
合理的问题，嗯，它
reasonable question um the the it
对这件事来说真的无关紧要
doesn't really matter for this
因为即使我们使用的是
construction because even if we're using
木筏在这里，我们还需要一方人来
raft here we still need one party to
做出一个可以与之相适应的决定
make a decision with which there can be
对于数据是如何存储的，没有异议
no disagreement about how the data is
在我们的上百个不同的
divided over our hundred different
复制组是正确的，所以您所知道的
replication groups right so all you know
我需要一个很大的系统
and I need kind of big system you're
拆分您的切分或拆分
splitting your sharding or splitting up
数据
the data
需要有人来决定数据是如何
somebody needs to decide how the data is
分配给不同的复制
assigned to the different replication
这必须随着时间的推移而改变，因为
groups this has to change over time as
您或多或少可以获得更多的硬件和更多的数据
you get more or less Hardware more data
或者随便什么，如果没有别的事的话
or whatever so if nothing else the
配置管理器说得很好
configuration manager is saying well
听着，你知道钥匙是以a或B开头的
look you know the keys start with a or B
先到这里，然后C或D甚至到这里
goes here or then C or D goes here even
如果你现在在这里使用Paxos，还有
if you use Paxos here now there's also
如果我们不吃东西的话这个小问题
this smaller question if we didn't eat
你知道我们应该用来做什么吗？
you know what should we use for
复制应为链式复制
replication should be chain replication
或者是睡衣或者木筏，或者其他任何东西，还有人
or paxos or raft or whatever and people
做一些有些人做的不同的事情
do different things some people do
实际使用基于Paxos的复制
actually use Paxos based replication
就像扳手一样，我想我们会
like spanner which I think we're gonna
看这学期晚些时候有这个
look at later in the semester has this
结构，但它实际上使用Paxos来
structure but it actually uses Paxos to
您已知的数据的复制权限
replicate rights for the data you know
您可能不想使用的原因是
the reason why you might not want to use
政治行动委员会是如此的漂浮，以至于它可以说是
PAC so so raft is that it's arguably
更高效地使用这条链
more efficient to use this chain
构造，因为它减少了负载。
construction because it reduces the load
可能是也可能不是
on the leader and that may or may not be
一个关键问题，一个值得支持的理由
a critical issue the a reason to favor
拉夫帕克索斯认为他们没有必要
rafter Paxos is that they do not have to
等待此链的滞后副本
wait for a lagging replica this chain
复制存在性能问题
replication has a performance problem
如果这些复制品中有一个速度很慢
that if one of these replicas is slow
因为即使有那么一刻
because even for a moment
你知道，因为每种价格都得
you know because every rate has to go
通过每个复制副本，即使是单个速度较慢的副本
through every replica even a single slow
复制副本放慢了所有产品的速度，一切正常
replica slows down all offer all right
行动和我可能会有很大的破坏力
operations and I can be very damaging
你知道如果你有数以千计的
you know if you have thousands of
服务器可能会在您指定的任何时间
servers probably did any given time you
我知道他们中的七个人出去吃午饭了
know seven of them are out to lunch or
不可靠或慢，因为某人
unreliable or slow because somebody's
安装新软件谁知道是什么
installing new software who knows what
所以说，如果有一件事是有一点破坏性的，那就是
and that so it's a bit damaging to have
每个请求在某种程度上都受到
every request be sort of limited by the
最慢的服务器，而Brafton paxos
slowest server whereas brafton paxos
嗯，这太棒了，比如说，如果其中一个
well it's so rad for example if one of
追随者是这样的，所以这无关紧要
the followers is so it doesn't matter
因为那个领袖只需要等待
because that leader only has to wait for
它不需要等待多数票
a majority it doesn't have to wait for
所有人，你知道，归根结底，他们都是
all of them you know ultimately they all
必须迎头赶上，但木筏要好得多
have to catch up but raft is much better
抵抗暂时性减速和一些
resisting transient slowdown and some
基于Paxos的系统，尽管不是真的
Paxos based systems although not really
筏子也很善于处理
raft are also good at dealing with the
复制品可能在
possibility that the replicas are in
不同的数据中心，可能还很远
different data centers and maybe far
因为你们只有
from each other and because you only
需要多数票你不需要
need a majority you don't have to
一定要等待确认
necessarily wait for acknowledgments
从远程数据中心，因此
from a distant data center and so that
还可以引导人们使用帕克斯木筏
can also leads people to use paxos raft
像多数人计划一样，而不是连锁计划
like majority schemes rather than chain
复制，但这在某种程度上是它
replication but this is sort of a it
很大程度上取决于你的工作量
depends very much on your workload and
你想要达到的目标，但这
what you're trying to achieve but this
整体架构很流行，我不知道
overall architecture is in I don't know
如果它是通用的，但它非常
if it's Universal but it's extremely
常见
common
就像故意的拓扑一样，没问题
like intentional topologies okay the for
A表示未中断的网络
a for a network that's not broken the
通常的假设是所有的
usual assumption is that all the
计算机之间可以通过
computers can talk to each other through
出现故障的网络的网络
the network for networks that are broken
因为有人踩到了电缆或者
because somebody stepped on a cable or
一些路由器错误配置了任何疯狂
some routers misconfigured any crazy
事情可能会发生
thing can happen
所以绝对是由于缺少配置
so absolutely due to miss configuration
你可以得到这样一种情况，你知道
you can get a situation where you know
这两个节点可以与
these two nodes can talk to the
配置管理器和
configuration manager and the
配置经理认为，先生，他们是
configuration managers think sir they're
但是他们不能互相交谈，所以
up but they can't talk to each other so
是的，而且这是这件事的杀手锏
yes and and that's a killer for this
正确，因为其他配置
right because other configuration
经理认为他们不能
manager thinks that are up they can't
互相交谈，男孩，就像是
talk to each other boy it's just like
这是一场灾难，如果你需要你的
it's a disaster and if you need your
系统对此有抵抗力，那么你
system to be resistant to that then you
需要有一个更谨慎的
need to have a more careful
您需要在其中加入逻辑的配置管理器
configuration manager you need logic in
说“天哪”的配置管理器
the configuration manager that says gosh
我只会用这些东西做成一条链子
I'm only gonna form a chain out of these
服务部门，我不仅可以和他们交谈，而且
services not only I can talk to that but
他们可以互相交谈，有点像
they can talk to each other and sort of
明确地检查了一下，我不知道
explicitly check and I don't know if
这很常见，我是说，我猜不是
that's common I mean I'm gonna guess not
但如果你特别小心你会想要
but if you were super careful you'd want
因为即使我们谈到
to because even though we talked about
网络分区，类似于
network partition that's like a
抽象，而在现实中，你可以得到
abstraction and in reality you can get
可以与谁交谈的任何组合
any combination of who can talk to who
其他的和一些可能会有很大的破坏性
else and some are may be very damaging
好的，我要结束了，下次再见
okay I'm gonna wrap up and see you next
星期
week